With more than 3 years of experience in Linux/Unix Administration, Networking, Database, Server Administration (Apache/Tomcat), DevOps Tools and master's degree in internetworking (Dalhousie University), I believe I am an ideal candidate to fill this position. My experience and knowledge are best suited with all the responsibilities and skills that you want in an ideal candidate for your company beside that I have good calling and chat etiquette to deal a client.

Currently I am working on a machine learning project apart from my curriculum. Which is helping me hone my programming skills further.

Skills Related to Job with Experiences:

Apache/Tomcat Server: 2+ yearsLinux/Unix Administration: 2+ years

Networking Engineer: 1+ yearsMySQL Database: 2 years

Html: 6+ monthsTesting: 6+ months

• System administration: 2+ years

Please review my attached resume for additional details regarding my expertise and career achievements. I will be waiting for a response on how my experience and background meets your needs.

Shubham Khulbe

Shubham Khulbe

skhulbe25@gmail.com

Halifax, NS. +1- 902-483-8332

A passionate learner, high-tech problem solver with professional experience of more than 3+ years. In addition to it I have a clear understanding of **Networking, Python, Database** and **Linux**

Education

Dalhousie University – (Meng) In Internetworking.

Halifax/NS - Canada

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- **OS**: Linux, UNIX, windows and Mac OS.
- **REDHAT:** RHEL 5,6 and 7
- **Security:** VPN, DNS, Firewall, TLS, SSL and IPsec.
- Database- MySQL, PL/SQL, Oracle
- Scripting: Bash Scripting (Basic)
- Computer Programming
 Python, HTML, C++, OOPS CONCEPT,
- Methodologies- Agile, Waterfall Testing- GUI, Manual testing, data validation, negative testing.
 Server: NFS SAMBA HTTPD. (installing and configuring)
- Switching- Strong
 Understanding of TCP/IP,
 L2/L3 switches, STP,
 VLAN, VTP, DNS and
 DHCP.
- Monitoring Tools:
 Wireshark, TCP Dump,
 Packet Tracer.

- Microsoft Server: Active
 Directory User Administration
 and Home Folders, Group
 Policy, File Security, Print
 Management
- Other: FTP, SFTP, SSH Entry Level (HTML, OOPS concept), GIT and GITHUB.
- **Supporting Tools** VMware, Log Me In, Team Viewer, Citrix.
- Networking-Cisco routers and switches (Lab experience) 2950 family switches, 3600 family routers.
- Routing Protocols- BGP, OSPF, RIP, EIGRP

Certification:

- CCNA Routing & Switching
- Linux Red hat RHCSA and RHCE Training.

Work Experience

Dalhousie University - Programming Lab Assistant (python)

Halifax | Present

- Assist student to complete their task and answer their queries about Programming tasks provided during the course.
- Conducted training sessions covering specified areas such as functions, classes, APIs etc.
- Helped students to troubleshoot the issues for their assignments.

Mahindra Comviva - TECHNICAL SUPPORT ENGINEER

New Delhi | 2015-2017

- Executed and performed remote IT technical support to overseas clients (APAC, Europe, & USA) as well as level 1 Technical Support to various businesses; Fostered strong professional relationships by asking appropriate technical questions to identify the problem and ensure it was efficiently, accurately, and consistently resolved.
- Installed software and resolved technical issues.
- Troubleshoot Symantec Endpoint protection issue by uninstalling Security Software, Virus Definitions, Remote Network Connections, and Host Checker disruptions and live update issues.
- Demonstrate skills and knowledge while working on tools like ITSM 7.6 remedy, SRMS and Service console, Active Directory, and Microsoft Exchange Server.
- Oversaw all queries and engineered troubleshooting issues related to mobility and all mobile devices configured for Outlook or Lync to support optimal user connectivity.
- Granted and revoked access as per the user and authorities' requirements for mobility servers, following all corporate security guidelines.
- Installed and managed various Tomcat servers as per the requests of clients.
- Managed databases of financial systems and implemented scripts and troubleshoot technical issues.

 Implemented and examined functionality and other features of OneDrive and related queries, providing valid functional and approachable resolutions while testing the same for Unisys internal deployment.

O4dSolution – System Analyst

New Delhi | 2014-2015

Client – CRIS (Indian Railways IT)

PROJECT: - E-Wallet and PRS: -

E-wallet refers to an electronic device or online service that allows an individual to make electronic transactions.

PRS: Passenger Railway System.

- Designed User Interface using Python, HTML as the front-end, and MySQL Database as the back-end
- My role in the project was to gather information prepare user and technical document, creatively and informatively Design dashboards and Web pages for e-Wallet Registration and Deposit module using JAVA & HTML, Deploying these Forms over Apache.
- Updating of test cases based on the implementation changes
- Applied patches and prepared Installation document.
- Validation of data through SQL queries (performing Manual Testing).
- Maintain existing databases
- Develop and implement procedures to ensure accuracy, timeliness, integrity and security of data.
- Performing Manual Testing against validation of data entry for each station, certain tests were made for e-wallet validation (PAN Card validation, web pages testing)

Project Works:

Ranking 311 issues based on priority to people

2013-2014

- Ranking 311 issues (Civic issues like potholes, broken streetlight, heavy traffic) based on the priority to citizens so the government can act on them accordingly.
- Machine learning concepts were used to prepare the system to self-prioritize the upcoming issues
- Python language was the base and its libraries were used to implement the machine learning algorithms.

Network automation

2017-2018

- Network automation tool which offers information retrieval, device management and implementation of BGP.
- GNS3 virtual environment was used to implement the topology with cisco router and switch images.
- Python language was the base with libraries like Napalm, Netmiko.

Walmart sales prediction

Present

- Prediction of sales using data from 40+ stores all over USA using machine learning algorithms.
- Factors like weather, temperature, department, day of the week, is it a holiday, fuel prices conclude to the prediction.
- Python language is the base to implement machine learning algorithms.